Guide to the Brooklyn periodical illustrations BCMS.0003
Brooklyn Collection
- Cemeteries
  - Pilot's Monument in Greenwood Cemetery, New York. Gleason's Pictorial Drawing Room Companion, August 14, 1852 (Box 3)
  - Receiving Tombs. Arbor Water [Greenwood Cemetery] (Box 3)
  - Southern Entrance – 1861 [Greenwood Cemetery] (Box 3)
  - Theaterbrand in Brooklyn am 5. Dezember 1876 – Begräbnis der Verunglückten auf Battle Hill, Greenwood-Friedhof, am 9 Dezember [Theater fire in Brooklyn on December 5, 1876 - Interment of the Victims on Battle Hill, Greenwood Cemetery, on December 9]. Frank Leslie's Illustrierte Zeitung, 1877 (Box 3)
  - Tool-House [Greenwood Cemetery] (Box 3)
  - Western Entrance – 1850 (From Within) [Greenwood Cemetery] (Box 3)
  - Western Entrance to Green-Wood Cemetery [2 copies]. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 3)
- Churches
  - The Brooklyn Bethel – Mission School for Children of the Poor, under Auspices of Plymouth Church. Harper's Weekly, 1870 January 29 (Box 7)
  - Brooklyn, L.I. – Meeting, in Plymouth Church, of the advisory council of congregational churches – Thomas G. Sherman making a statement of the case of Plymouth Church, on the second day of the meeting, February 16th. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, March 4, 1876 (Box 7)
  - Brooklyn, NY – The Presbyterian General Assembly at the Tabernacle. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, June 10, 1876 (Box 7)
  - The Brooklyn Tabernacle – Appearance of the Ruins on Monday Morning, May 14th. – From a Photograph Made Expressly for Leslie's Weekly by J.C. Hemment. Leslie's Weekly, May 24, 1894 (Box 7)
  - Burning of the Brooklyn Tabernacle / Brooklyn Tabernacle – Interior View. Harper's Weekly, 1873 (Box 7)
  - Centennial Baptist Church. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 7)
  - Central Baptist Church, E.D. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 7)
  - Central Congregational Church, Ormond Place. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 7)
  - Central M.E. Church. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 7)
  - The Ceremony of Laying the Corner Stone of the Roman Catholic Cathedral of the Immaculate Conception, on Lafayette, Vanderbilt, Clermont and Greene Avenues, Brooklyn, L.I., June 21. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, July 11, 1868 (Box 7)
  - The Church of the Holy Trinity. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 7)
  - Church of the Pilgrims, Henry Street, Cor. Remsen. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 7)
  - Emanuel Baptist Church. The American Architect and Building News, April 23, 1888 (Box 7)
  - First Baptist Church. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 7)
  - First Methodist Episcopal Church, Brooklyn, N.Y.; Sands Street Memorial; John Welch, Architect. The American Architect and Building News, February 18, 1893 (Box 7)
  - First Place Methodist Episcopal; St.John's Methodist Episcopal Church. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 7)
  - First Reformed Church of Brooklyn. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 7)
  - Fleet Street M.E. Church. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 7)
  - Grace Methodist Episcopal Church. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 7)
  - Greenwood Baptist Church. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 7)
  - Lafayette Avenue Presbyterian Church. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 7)
  - The Lee Avenue Baptist Church, Brooklyn, N.Y. The Manufaturer and Builder, 1872 (Box 7)
  - Meeting in Plymouth Church of the advisory council of Congressional churches – Thomas G. Shearman making a statement of the case of Plymouth Church on the second day of the Meeting, February 16th. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, March 4, 1876 (Box 7)
  - The Church of the Pilgrim, corner of Clinton and Remsen Streets, Brooklyn. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper (Box 7)
  - The New Brooklyn Tabernacle on Schermerhorn Street, Rev. T. De Witt Talmage, Pastor. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, March 7, 1874 (Box 7)
  - New York - New Chapel of the Church of the Pilgrims in Brooklyn. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, January 18, 1879 (Box 7)
  - Nostrand Avenue M.E. Church. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 7)
  - Old Dutch Reformed Church, 1776. Drawn by Miss Elizabeth Sleight in 1808; copied from the original drawing by G.Hayward; for McCloskey's Manual of the City of Brooklyn, 1864 (Box 7)
  - The Old Franklin Avenue Presbyterian Church. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 7)
  - Park Avenue Primitive Methodist Church. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 7)
  - Pierrepont Street Baptist Church. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 7)
  - Plymouth Church. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 7)
  - Puritan Church. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 7)
  - Recent Additions to Churches of Brooklyn. Drawn by Hughson Hawley. Harper's Weekly, May 26, 1888 (Box 7)
  - Roman Catholic Church of St. John the Evangelist, Brooklyn, New York. The American Architect (Box 7)
  - The Ross Street Presbyterian Church, Brooklyn, N.Y. The Manufacturer and Builder, 1872 (Box 7)
  - The Second Breuckelen Church, 1766. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 7)
  - Simpson M.E. Church. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 7)
  - Sixth Avenue Baptist Church. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 7)
  - South Third Street Presbyterian Church. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 7)
  - Trial of the Rev. T. De Witt Talmage, Charged with Falsehood and Deceit, before the Presbytery of Brooklyn—The Accused Demanding a Rigid Investigation. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, April 12, 1879 (Box 7)
  - View of the Ruins of the Famous Brooklyn Tabernacle, Destroyed by Fire October 13th. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, October 26, 1889 (Box 7)
  - Washington Avenue Baptist Church. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 7)
- Clubs
  - Brooklyn Whist Club. Harper's Weekly, undated (Box 3)
  - Das neue heim des Union League Club zu Brooklyn [The new home of the Union League Club of Brooklyn]. Frank Leslie's Illustrierte Zeitung (Box 3)
  - Fifth Annual Exhibition at the Riding Academy in Brooklyn – The "Hungarian Post." Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, March 29, 1873 (Box 3)
  - Reception of Lt.-Com Gorringe, U.S.N., by Anglo-Saxon Lodge, No 137, F and AM, Brooklyn, September 1st, Explaining the Masonic Emblems on the Egyptian Obelisk. From a Sketch by Albert Berghaus. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, September 18, 1880 (Box 3)
  - Summer Encampment of State G.A.R. at Brooklyn – Sounding the Bugle-Calls in Music Hall, July 28th. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, August 14, 1880 (Box 3)
  - The Union League Club-House, Bedford Ave., Brooklyn, N.Y.; P.J. Lauritzen, Architect. The American Architect and Building News, November 14, 1891 (Box 3)
- Coney Island
  - After Clams on Coney Island. Drawn by Albert Berghaus. Harper's Weekly, 1884 March 8 (Box 7)
  - American Excursion Coney Island Sightseeing Tour. Sterlip Press, Inc, NY. (Box 7)
  - American Medical Association Sailing Around Coney Island [German language]. Frank Leslie's Illustrierte Zeitung, June 4, 1880 (Box 7)
  - Amerikanische Skizzen: Am Badestrand von Coney Island bei Neuyork [American sketches: At the beach of Coney Island near New York] [women riding donkeys in the water]. Frank Leslie's Illustrierte Zeitung, August 23, 1879 (Box 7)
  - Art and Nature at the West End of Coney Island [2 copies]. Harper's Weekly, July 16, 1887 (Box 7)
  - An Artist's Holiday Notes at Coney Island. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, July 6, 1889 (Box 7)
  - An Artist's Impressions of the New Coney, 1903 (Box 7)
  - The Beach at Coney Island. Drawn by Ben Day. Harper's Weekly, August 17, 1867 (Box 7)
  - Commissary Department of Big Summer Resort Hotel, Manhattan Beach, Coney Island. Photographs by Harriet Quimby [2 copies]. Leslie's Weekly, July 5, 1906 (Box 7)
  - Coney Island and the Crowned Heads: Why Shouldn't the Wearied Monarchs of Europe Enjoy a Plunge in Our Republican Waters? Puck, circa 1883 (Box 7)
  - Coney Island, beliebter Badeplatz am antlantichen Ozean, nahe New York [Coney Island, beloved bathing place on the Atlantic Ocean, near New York]. Frank Leslie's Illustrierte Zeitung, August 8, 1888 (Box 7)
  - The Coney Island Concourse. Harper's Weekly, August 4, 1877 (Box 7)
  - Coney Island, New York, on the Atlantic Ocean – Manhattan Beach Hotel [German language]. Frank Leslie's Illustrierte Zeitung, circa 1879 (Box 7)
  - Das Seebad Coney Island bei New York. Deutsche Illustrtirte Zeitung (Box 7)
  - The Encroachments of the Sea at Coney island—Moving back the Great Hotel at Brighton Beach. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, January 14, 1888 (Box 7)
  - Enjoyment of Midsummer Throngs in New York. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Weekly, July 11, 1907 (Box 7)
  - Famous Coney Island Where New York's Heated Millions Find Relief. Leslie's Weekly (Box 7)
  - High Tide at Coney Island, 1895 (Box 7)
  - An Idle Hour on Coney Island. Harper's Bazaar, August 28, 1880 (Box 7)
  - The Joys of Saturday-Sunday Land. Harper's Weekly Advertiser, 1910 [?] (Box 7)
  - Kinder im Bade, Scene nahe dem Sanitorium zu Coney Island [Children bathing, scene near the Sanitorium at Coney Island]. Frank Leslie's Illustrierte Zeitung, August 10, 1889 (Box 7)
  - A Lesson for the Uninitiated – Three-Card Monte Players on Coney Island Beach. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, August 31, 1867 (Box 7)
  - Manhattan Beach Hotel, Coney Island. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 7)
  - The New Coney Island—Night Views of "Dreamland" and "Luna Park." Harper's Weekly, 1904 [?] (Box 7)
  - New York's New Summer Amusement Resort: Some of the Attractions of Dreamland. The Theatre Magazine, 1904 [?] (Box 7)
  - New York's Two Most Famous Midsummer Resorts: The Masses Delight in the Variegated Attractions of Coney Island, While the More Select Ones Crowd to the Cool Retreats of Central Park. Leslie's Weekly, July 30, 1903 (Box 7)
  - On Coney Island – View from the Observatory, Looking East. Drawn by Charles Graham. Harper's Weekly, August 11, 1883 (Box 7)
  - On the Iron Pier, Coney Island—The Rush for the Last Boat. Harper's Weekly, July 29, 1882 (Box 7)
  - On The Way To Coney Island. Drawn by T. De Thulstrup. Harper's Weekly, 1886 (Box 7)
  - Oriental Hotel, Manhattan Beach, Coney Island. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 7)
  - Our Summer Resorts—Sketches at Coney Island. Drawn by T. de Thulstrup. Harper's Weekly, August 6, 1881 (Box 7)
  - The People's Great Summer Resort—the Latest Improvements on Coney Island—Brighton Beach and its Attractions. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, August 24, 1878 (Box 7)
  - Political Coney Island [centerfold in an entire issue]. Puck, August 10, 1887 (Box 7)
  - Posters of Steeplechase Park [4 posters, oversize. Located in collection flat file] (Box 7)
  - Saturday's Half-Holiday Crowd on the Beach at Coney Island: New York's Popular Breathing Spot, To Which It's Millions of All Conditions Flock During the Heat of the Day. Leslie's Weekly (Box 7)
  - Scene at a Coney Island Sanitarium – The Children's Bathing Hour. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, August 10, 1889 (Box 7)
  - Scenes and Incidents at Coney Island.—Life-Savers at Work— "Pull Hearty, my Boys!" Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, August 28, 1886 (Box 7)
  - Scenes and Incidents on Coney Island. Drawn by W.A. Rogers. Harper's Weekly, August 10, 1878 (Box 7)
  - Sea-side bathing at the Coney Island Beach. The Daily Graphic, 1873 (Box 7)
  - Sleighing on the New Ocean Parkway from Prospect Park, Brooklyn, to the Atlantic—a Trot on the Coney Island Beach. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, February 10, 1877 (Box 7)
  - St. George's Inn: Boulevard, Coney Island: Bruce Price, Architect. The American Architect and Building News, June 25, 1880 (Box 7)
  - The Storm on Coney Island. From Sketches by H.M. Eaton. Harper's Weekly, February 28, 1885 (Box 7)
  - Summer Diversions at the Seaside – A Coasting Party At Coney Island – "More Scared Than Hurt." Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, July 24, 1886 (Box 7)
  - The "Three-Card Monte" – A Scene On Coney Island. Sketched by Stanley Fox (Box 7)
  - Under way for Coney Island. Harper's Young People, October 17, 1882 (Box 7)
  - A Visit to Coney Island. Harper's Weekly, September 12, 1891 (Box 7)
  - The Warfare on the Route to Coney Island, 1902 [?] (Box 7)
  - Women Bathing at Coney Island [Badende Frauen…] [German Language]. Frank Leslie's Illustrierte Zeitung, 1882 (Box 7)
- Crime
  - The Arrest of the Abductor of the Girl Lizzie Selden, in Brooklyn August 31st. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 1882 September 9 (Box 3)
  - Base Metal Coinage—A Gang of Counterfeiters in Brooklyn Molding Imitation Silver Dollars. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 1889-01-12 (Box 3)
  - The Bay Ridge Robbers – The Thieves Firing on Mr. Van Brunt. From Sketches by Theo. R. Davis. Harper's Weekly, 1875-01-02 (Box 3)
  - The Brooklyn Kidnappers: Little Lizzie Selden decoyed from her home by a strange woman, who is captured after a general hunt. The National Police Gazette: New York, 1882-09-16 (Box 3)
  - Brutal Double Murder in Husted's stables, Skillman Street, Brooklyn Thursday, May 13. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 1858-05-22 (Box 3)
  - He Concluded to Skip: A Suspected Murderer Named Krause Makes a Swift and Successful Escape from the Raymond Street Jail, Brooklyn. The National Police Gazette: New York, 1888-01-24 (Box 3)
  - The Kelsey Mystery. Scenes of the Huntington (L.I.) Excitement. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 1873-09-20 (Box 3)
- Disasters
  - Brooklyn Theatre Broadside. Brooklyn Theatre, This Week, Positively the Last Times in Brooklyn of the Two Orphans With All Its Original Scenes and Cast [located in collection flat file], 1876 (Box 3)
  - Brooklyn Public School Catastrophe – Scene At The Stairway Opening on Navy Street, Where the Children Were Suffocated to Death. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 1858 January 30 (Box 3)
  - The Brooklyn Theatre Conflagration. The room of the Property Clerk at the Brooklyn Headquarters – Friends of the Missing Identifying Relics Found in the Ruins or on the Bodies of the Victims [2 copies; 1 German language; 1 English]. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 1876-12-30 (Box 3)
  - Burning of the Brooklyn Tabernacle. Harper's Weekly, 1873-01-11 (Box 3)
  - The Burning of the Brooklyn Theatre, December 5th – Scene from the Stage at the First Alarm of fire – The Actors Endeavoring to Prevent a Panic [numerous illustrations also included within the issue]. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 1876-12-23 (Box 3)
  - Burning of the Brooklyn Theatre – Scene at the Washington Street Entrance. Harper's Weekly, 1876-12-23 (Box 3)
  - Collision on the Hudson River Between The Steamer Knickerbocker and Sloop Stephen Raymond – Captain Drowned. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 1859-04-16 (Box 3)
  - Destructive Fire in Fuhman Street, Under the Heights, Brooklyn, NY., Undated. (Box 3)
  - Destruction of the Fifth Avenue Theater, New York, in 1873., Undated. (Box 3)
  - Explosion at Ames & Moulton's Hat Factory. Harper's Weekly, 1860-02-11 (Box 3)
  - Explosion of Two Boilers at Jewell's Mills, Brooklyn, N.Y., February 16, 1882. Scientific American, 1882-05-20 (Box 3)
  - The Fatal Accident on the New Elevated Railroad, on Broadway, in the Eastern District of Brooklyn, Tuesday Morning, the 14th inst—A Section of the Structure, with Derricks, Construction-Car, Boiler etc, Falls upon a Horse Car Filled with Passengers. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 1888-02-18 (Box 3)
  - February's Fury – Freaks of the Great Winter Storm At Long Branch and Coney Island. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 1880-02-21 (Box 3)
  - Funeral Procession for the Victims of the Brooklyn Theatre Fire [German language]. Frank Leslie's Illustrierte Zeitung, 1876-12-19 (Box 3)
  - The Great Fire in Brooklyn, July 15, 1864. Harper's Weekly, 1864-07-30 (Box 3)
  - Horrible Death of a Number of Firemen at the Conflagration on Furman Street, Brooklyn, April 4 – The Roofs Giving Way and Precipitating the Victims among the Ruins of the Warerooms Underneath. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 1865-04-22 (Box 3)
  - Kamp mit Kaiffifdien in der gai New York nahe Fort Layfayette. Frank Leslie's Illustrierte Zeitung, 1880 (Box 3)
  - The Burning of the Ferry-Boat, Idaho, on Monday Evening, Nov. 26th, in the East River, N.Y., opposite Williamsburgh, Long Island Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 1866-12-15 (Box 3)
  - The Late Fire in Brooklyn. Shingle Yard Fire on Van Brunt Street near Summit. Illustrated News, 1853-07-02 (Box 3)
  - New York, - Fatal Collision on Lond Island Sound, June 11th - The "City of New York" picking up the passengers of the "Narragansett" after the collision of hte latter with the "Stonington" Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 1880-06-26 (Box 3)
  - The Recent Destructive Tornado in Brooklyn – Explosion of the Gasometers of the Citizen's Gas Company, Smith and Fifth Streets. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 1889-01-19 (Box 3)
  - Ruins after the Late Fire in Brooklyn [Fire at 359 Fulton Street]. Illustrated News, 1853-06-04 (Box 3)
  - Shocking Scene at a Fire in Brooklyn, N.Y., on February 6, 1859 [Fire at Fulton and Elm]. Harper's Weekly, 1859-02-19 (Box 3)
  - The Terrible Disaster at the New York Approach of the East River Bridge, May 30th – Removing the Bodies of the Killed and Injured. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, June 9, 1883. (Box 3)
  - Thrilling Scene at a Recent Fire in Greenpoint. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 1882-12-09 (Box 3)
  - Wreck of the Schooner "Emma Jane" in Jamaica Bay During the store of Dec. 30, 1895. Collier's Weekly, 1896-01-09 (Box 3)
- Distilleries
  - Swill Tanks Connected With Husted's Distillery, Skillman Street, Brooklyn. Filling the Casks with Distillery Slops, to Take to the Cow-Stables of the Long-Island Farmers. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 1858 May 15 (Box 3)
  - The Whiskey War in the City of Brooklyn, New York [Fifth Ward]. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 1869 December 25 (Box 3)
- Ferries
  - America Revisited by our Special Artist. The Illustrated News of the World, 1890 March 29 (Box 3)
  - Atlantic Street, or South Ferry. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 3)
  - Dangers of Ferry Navigation During Heavy Fog – Scene on the East River – A Narrow Escape [color]. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 1887-12-24 (Box 3)
  - Don't Jump! – A Warning oft Repeated, Little Heeded. – Narrow Escape of a Young Lady from Being Crushed between the Boat and Bridge at Fulton Ferry, N.Y., Undated. (Box 3)
  - The Effect of the Gale of Dec. 27th and 28th on the Ferries – lowering loaded wagons on board the ferry boat at the foot of South Sevent Street, Williamsburgh L.I., 1866 (Box 3)
  - The Ferry at Brooklyn, New York. Print published by Geo. Virtue, 1839 [2 copies; 1 b&w; 1 color]., Undated. (Box 3)
  - Ferry House at Foot of Hamilton Avenue. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 3)
  - Ferry House at Foot of Montague Street. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 3)
  - Ferry Mismanagement – Fatal and Terrible Collision between the Boats "Hamilton" and "Union," at Fulton Ferry, New York City, November 14th, 1868. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 1868-11-28 (Box 3)
  - Homeward Rush. Drawn by W.P. Snyder. Harper's Weekly, 1892-04-23 (Box 3)
  - La debacle des glaces, a New York. Vue prise de la riviere orientale [The Icebreaker, New York. View taken from the East River]. L'Univers Illustre, undated. (Box 3)
  - Meeting of the Ferry Investigating Committee at Washington Hall, Williamsburg, Long Island, On Monday and Tuesday, Feb. 11th and 12th. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 1867-03-02 (Box 3)
  - Moving the Brick Ferry House of the 39th Street Brooklyn Ferry. Scientific American, 1893-02-11 (Box 3)
  - On the Ferry. Copyright 1898 by Charles Scribner's Sons (Box 3)
  - The Twentieth Century Woman on a New York Ferry-Boat. Drawn by G.W. Peters. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Weekly, 1907-03-21 (Box 3)
  - Where Two Ends Meet – Scene on the Pier at Twenty-Sixth Street, East River, New York – Drawn by T. De Thulstrup. Harper's Weekly, 1891 (Box 3)
  - Zusammenstoss zweier Fahrzeuge auf dem East River am 3 Mai 1875 [Collision of two vehicles on the East River, May 3 1875]. Frank Leslie's Illustrierte Zeitung (Box 3)
- Fire Department
  - A big blaze at Hunter's Point – a constant menace to New York and Brooklyn. Harper's Weekly, 1884 February 23 (Box 3)
  - "Fire!" Response of the Insurance Patrol., Undated. (Box 3)
  - General View of Fire Alarm Headquarters, Brooklyn, N.Y. [various other photographs of the Fire Alarm Headquarters included as well]. Fire and Water, 1896-09-26 (Box 3)
  - The Great Conflagration at Hunter's Point, Long Island Destruction of oil works and shipping May 25th. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 1869-06-12 (Box 3)
  - The Late Procession of the Fire Department, Brooklyn, N.Y.; View of Firemen's Hall, Brooklyn, N.Y. Gleason's Pictorial Drawing Room Companion, undated. (Box 3)
  - New York Harbor. Fire, Police and Tug-Boats Saving the Shipping of Brooklyn—Towing the Grain Elevator "Transporter" into the Harbor, on the Night of October 4th. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 1878-10-19 (Box 3)
  - The Veteran Firemen of Brooklyn – Portraits of Leading Members of the Old Volunteer Department, With some of the Department Relics. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 1888-02-11 (Box 3)
- Industry
  - 700-Foot Floating Dock of the Morse Dry Dock, Brooklyn. Scientific American, 1900 April 21 (Box 8)
  - Ansicht der Yard bei den Brennerei-Stallungen…in Brooklyn. [View of the yard at the distillery stables...in Brooklyn]. Frank Leslie's Illustrierte Zeitung, 1858-05-22 (Box 8)
  - Asbestos Works of the H.W. Johns Manufacturing Company [various ill.; 2 copies; 1b&w, 1 color]. Scientific American, 1881-02-26 (Box 8)
  - Atlantic Docks and Basin. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 8)
  - Brooklyn Warehouse and Storage Company., Undated. (Box 8)
  - The Brooklyn Warehouse and Storage Company. Harper's Weekly, undated. (Box 8)
  - C.H. Reynold's Coal and Wood Yards. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 8)
  - Charles A. Schieren & Co.'s Manufactory. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 8)
  - Charles S. Higgins' Soap Manufactory. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 8)
  - Columbian Iron Works. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 8)
  - D. Appleton & Co.'s Book Manufactory. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 8)
  - Downing & Lawrences' Marine Railways and Ship Yard. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 8)
  - Dow's Grain Stores, Brooklyn, U.S.A. Engineering, 1883-11-02 (Box 8)
  - Duc's Mechanical Atomizer- Made at the Continental Works, Brooklyn. N.Y. Scientific American, 1882-03-11 (Box 8)
  - E. Ketcham & Co's Tin Ware Manufactory, Brooklyn. Office & Warerooms, 100 Beekman St., & 289 Pearl St., NY., 1874 (Box 8)
  - Exposure of the Milk Trade – general view of Wilson and Husted's Distilleries and cow stables, on Flushing Avenue and Skillman Street, Brooklyn. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 1858-05-08 (Box 8)
  - Exposure of the Swill-Milk Trade. – Interior of the Cow-Stables Connected with the Distillery Corner of Flushing Avenue and Skillman Streets, Brooklyn. Supplement to Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 1874-11-28 (Box 8)
  - Grain Elevator, Atlantic Dock, Brooklyn. Harper's Weekly, 1871-05-20 (Box 8)
  - Grain Ships Laid up in Gowanus Creek—Waiting for Cargoes. Harper's Weekly, 1880-04-10 (Box 8)
  - The Great Dry Docks at the Erie Basin, Brooklyn, N.Y. Scientific American Supplement No. 444, 1884-07-05 (Box 8)
  - Handling the Grain Crop at the Port of New York Scientific American, 1897-11-20 (Box 8)